<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Servers>
    <ServerGroup Name="28 Alphas Later" Logo="https://media.discordapp.net/attachments/1155647724478275614/1180961617417085000/background.png" Description="Will you survive?">
        <Server Name="28 Alphas Later" Logo="https://media.discordapp.net/attachments/1155647724478275614/1180961617417085000/background.png">
            <Description>28 Alphas Later 


28 Alphas Later - now for v3.0
Will you survive?

The idea behind this mod is to slow progression, and generally extend the time for a playthrough, while keeping the vanilla look and feel.


25/6/26 mod version 3.0.0.0

Known Issues: OCBMicroSplat is **not** updated as yet, so custom ore nodes have vanilla textures.
 
Some UI issues with all passive collectors. Doesn't affect functionality, and will be fixed in a future update/fix.

*** CAUTION ***
Will require a new save, and is only compatible with base game version 3.0.0 and above.

# FEATURES 

## GENERAL GAMEPLAY

 - Player starts with a new debuff - Despair.

 - As your despair increases, so will your abilities be negatively affected. If despair reaches 100%, you'll be seconds from death.

 - Conversely, if you can manage your despair well, you'll receive buffs for remaining positive.

 - The despair indicator on the HUD will fill as your despair grows, and will change colour to indicate the level of your despair.

 - If you're able to manage your despair and have a more positive outlook, the icon on the HUD will change, as will the fill colour to indicate your levels of positivity.

 - Despair can also be checked from the player information screen.


Despair is dynamically affected by various factors, including:

1. Darkness. Too dark, and your Despair will increase dramatically. Torches, helmet lights and flashlights will mitigate this. Use these in conjunction with a campfire for the best effect.
2. Temperature. If you’re freezing or sweltering, your Despair will also increase dramatically. Find shelter!
3. Environment: Varying degrees of “wetness” will change how Despair affects you, as will your shelter. If you’re warm, dry, sheltered, well lit or resting on a bed or bedroll, AND near an operating campfire,forge or chem station, you can effectively “treat” Despair.
4. Hunger and thirst affect how quickly your despair increases. Starvation/dehydration will drastically increase the rate at which you become affected by despair.
5. Injuries will affect how quickly your despair increases.
6. There is medication in trader stock and rare medical loot to treat your despair.
7. There is also lavender growing wild, which can be collected to make your own lavender seeds, and is also used to make Lavender Oil in a cooking pot at a campfire. Treats 3% Despair.
8. All food has a positive effect. The better the food, the more effective the treatment.
9. Killing zombies and animals will reduce your overall despair. Conversely, getting hit by enemies will increase it.
10. Being in close proximity to zombies increases your Despair. The tougher the zombie, the worse the effect. The effect is compounded, so the more zombies there are, the worse it'll be.
11. Player “wellness”. Your maximum health will also slow down the effects of despair. Every 10 additional health slows down the rate at which Despair affects you.
12. The morale booster from the drone will decrease the rate at which despair affects you.
13. The trader has an effect. Being close to a trader will slow down and/or reduce your Despair.
14. The perk "From the Shadows" also affects the way Despair affects you at NIGHT. The more points in the perk, the less Despair affects you at night.

 - Headshots! Zombies take **maximum** damage from headshots; however, they do take *small* damage if you miss the head.

 - Zombies **DON'T** bleed. Nothing undead takes bleed damage.

 - There are more zombies in the world. Biomes are gamestaged, which means zombies get tougher and their number increases as you level up.

 - Nights are dangerous and a lot darker, downtown is **much** more dangerous.
 
## WATER rework

### Water has been completely overhauled for this version of the mod.

1. There are no jars. You start with a reusable canteen, which can be filled from water sources in the world, like sinks, toilets, water coolers etc.
2. There are 3 types of drink containers - a canteen for water, a thermal cup/mug for teas and coffees, and a sports bottle for juices and smoothies.
3. The blue barrels found in the world can be picked up, repaired, and placed as water storage. A single barrel holds 30 water, and 4 stack pallet holds 120.
4. Standing water in the world cannot be used for anything except filling buckets and drinking with an empty hand.
5. In order to cook any recipe that requires water, you need clean water in your canteen.
6. Water and other drinks cannot be mixed in the same container. If you have murky water in your canteen, you'll need to store it, boil it, or dump it before you can fill the canteen with another type of water.
7. Same method applies to other drinks containers. You can't mix coffee and Blackstrap coffee, nor can you mix tea. You'll have to drink it first to use the cup, or find another cup. You also can't mix yucca juice with yucca smoothies.
8. Thermal cups, sports bottles, and additional canteens can be found in loot, or at traders.
9. Bottles found in the world can be picked up, and are needed to craft beer. Bottles are always returned when drinking beer, and are not craftable.

## INVENTORY

 - You have a **MAXIMUM** bag capacity of 60 slots, and you start with 30 unencumbered slots unlocked.
 
 - To increase your inventory capacity, you need to find bag upgrades in the world, which will unlock an additional 10 slots of inventory space per upgrade.
 
 - You have to use the bag upgrades in the correct order. You cannot unlock the biggest backpack with out first unlocking the big backpack AND the bigger backpack.

 - There are schematics to be found or purchased from traders to unlock recipes for crafting the bag upgrades.

 - Encumberance works exactly as it does in vanilla - the bag upgrades only unlock *usable* inventory space. You'll still need Pack Mule or pocket mods to reduce encumberance. 
 
 
## BLOCKS/WORKSTATIONS

 - The workbench now has slots for a wrench, hammer, ratchet, impact driver, nail gun, and ammo press. These tools are needed to craft a lot of items, and some items have been moved from inventory crafting to workbench crafting.

 - The workbench ammo press tool is required for crafting ammunition.

 - The workbench now has its 'combine' function restored. Combine identical items in your workbench to repair them, and if they're durable enough, improve their quality. Remove mods from items before combining so as not to lose them.

 - The cement mixer now requires gasoline to work.

 - The sawmill. Unlocked at the same level as the workbench, use the sawmill to craft wood logs into wood planks. Wrench a tablesaw for a sawblade, or purchase a sawblade from a trader.

 - If you have the required book, existing ammo can be crafted into stacks.

 - Glue requires a beaker to craft at the campfire.
 
 - Chicken coop. Catch a wild chicken and place it in a chicken coop to produce eggs. A Heatlamp for speeding up collection and Nesting for increasing quantity can be purchased or unlocked with workstation progression.
 
 - Beehive. Find a bee in tree stumps by harvesting the stump. Will produce honey over time when placed in a beehive. A Bee Smoker for speeding up collection and a Bee Frame for increasing quantity can be purchased or unlocked with workstation progression.


## BUFFS/DEBUFFS

 - Snakes and Spider zombies will **envenom** you when they attack. Kill snakes to extract their venom, which can be used to make antivenom. Antivenom crafting is unlocked by default, and it can appear in loot and trader stock.

 - The Wasteland biome is very, **VERY** dangerous. Filled with all manner of new enemies - and a *lot* of them.

 - Despair medication (Lavender, St. John’s Wort and Lithium) can be found in medical loot, and in trader stock. Lavender oil can be crafted from lavender flowers and used to treat despair.

 - Insulated liner and cooling mesh mods for armour are back. Armour has very little weather protection now, so for permanent resistance to hot and cold, these armour mods will be essential.
You can also use the Well Insulated perk, or temporarily use coffee and Blackstrap coffee to keep you warm, and yucca juice and yucca smoothies to keep you cool.


## ZOMBIES/ENEMIES

 - Bears and wolves are back in the forest.

 - Hazmat zombies are now immune to burning.

 - New **Bunker Buster** zombie. Only appears during bloodmoon(s), and can appear from the very first Bloodmoon. You’ll want to take it out quickly … think of it as a 'light' demolition zombie.

 - Demolition zombies appear at a much earlier gamestage.

 - New **Frozen** zombie variant. Slightly tougher, slightly slower, slightly more XP, and take slightly more damage than their "normal" counterparts. If they touch you, you'll be freezing! You can negate this by maxing out the Well Insulated perk.  Found in the snow biome.

 - New **Rotting** zombie variant. They have lower HP, lower XP reward, and they take more damage. Found in the forest biome.

 - New **Cowboy** zombie variant. Similar to "normal" zombies, these enemies are exclusive to the desert biome, identifiable by their cowboy hats. They are hot to the touch, and getting hit by them will overheat you briefly.

 - New **Mutant** zombie variant. Very tough zombies, with regenerative properties, populating the wasteland. 

 - All "fatties" (Big Mama, tourist etc.) explode and are filled with a substance that’s irresistible to all zombies. If you are within range when they explode, they’ll cover you in this stuff - and attract other zombies. Cop and vulture vomit also has this effect.


## FOOD/FARMING

 - All canned food found in loot, vending machines, and trader stock is **uncooked.** Cook it to make it safe to eat, or eat it and run the risk of food poisoning ...

 - No food, *except* Sham Chowder, replenishes health - just food and water.

 - Farming rework. You need a hoe to till the ground to plant seeds. Use the hoe with *at least* **10** fertiliser **IN YOUR INVENTORY** to upgrade the tilled ground. Fertilized terrain yields the same amount of crops as a farmplot.

 - Farm Plots require fertiliser and nails to craft, are crafted in the workbench with a hammer,  and are the same fertile level as fertilised ground.

 - Fertiliser is craftable in the cement mixer and chem station, and is in *some* trader stock. It can also be obtained by shovelling pallets of fertilizer bags.

 - Wild plants can be picked up - press ‘E’ by default to pick them up. Picking up crops now respects Living off the Land bonuses, as well as equipped Farmer gear.

 - New plant - lavender. Purple flower found growing in the wild and in some POIs. Seeds can be crafted from lavender flowers, no unlock required. Lavender flowers can be found in loot and trader stock, and Lavender seeds in trader stock.

 - All plants and crops in POIs are dead, *except* the Wasteland, where some corn has mutated into Super Corn. For a plentiful supply of crops, you'll need to grow your own.

 - Wellness. Your player's max health and stamina is directly affected by the food and drink you consume. The better the food or drink, the more your max health and increase. Conversely, receiving critical injuries or debuffs will lower your wellness.

 - Hobo Stew requires canned cat food or dog food.

 - Red tea and Goldenrod tea require a higher ingredient count.

 - All candy has been removed.


## PROGRESSION

 - All tool and weapon skills are now governed by action skills.

 - All attribute masteries have been removed, and some skills from books, like Bar Brawling, have been re-worked.
 
 - **Magazines have been COMPLETELY removed and replaced with Research Papers. These papers allow you to unlock crafting items and levels in any order you please, as long as you have enough.**
**Research papers are mostly found in zombie corpse loot, and everywhere magazines and books would usually be found, plus a few other places too.**
**You must have research papers in your inventory to unlock crafting skills, and the cost of skills scales as your crafting skill increases.**


## RESOURCES

 - Trees no longer give wood, they give wood logs, scraps, and branches. Logs can be placed and then chopped with an axe for wood, or use the sawmill to do it quicker and better.

 - Primitive weapons and ammo are now made from wood scraps, branches, plant fibres, and/or stone.


## GEAR

 - All portable light sources have a *fuel* requirement. Electrical devices like helmet lights and flashlights require **batteries**, while torches and burning shafts require **gasoline**. You need a battery or fuel in your inventory to activate these items, and when the battery or fuel expires, it will need to be replaced.

 - The helmet purifier mod has changed. It is now a housing unit for a **craftable water filter**, which has ***limited*** uses. As with the portable light sources, you'll need a water filter in your inventory to activate it, and once it expires, it will need replacing.


## VEHICLES

 - All vehicles **CANNOT** be picked up once placed - so choose your placement carefully.

 - Five new vehicles, a scooter, a dirt bike, a quad bike, a dune buggy, and a semi truck. The semi truck has a craftable trailer mod, which doubles it's inventory capacity.


# Contributors:

**Particle systems/Unity edits 				- Author: redbeardt**

**60 slot backpack							- Author: Khaine**

**Khelldon Custom Menu 						- Author: Khelldon**

**Logical Loot (xml code)					- Author: izPreBuilt**

**Hybrid Action skills						- Author: JoeSloMo**

**WMMVideoOptions							- Author: w00kien00kie**

**OcbMicroSplat								- Author: OCB Maurice**

						
Also a huge thank you to Frantic_Dan and redbeardt for the custom HUD base code and main menu localization changes, to Tormented Emu for retexturing of weapons, Frantic_Dan for xml contributions, and to YubiNashi and Frantic_Dan for ideas/balancing and playtesting - and to you, for giving my mod a try :)
			
            </Description>
            <Discord></Discord>
            <Donate></Donate>
            <EAC>Disabled</EAC>
            <Version>Latest</Version>
            <DownloadMode>Clone</DownloadMode>
            <Downloads>
                <Download>https://github.com/HellsJanitor/28-Alphas-Later-for-3.0</Download>
            </Downloads>
        </Server>
    </ServerGroup>
</Servers>